So I want to pass in a color into the word adapter so
أرغب في وضع لون على موائم النص حتى
all the words in that category have the same background color.
تظهر جميع النصوص في هذه الفئة بنفس لون الخلفية.
So to do this I will need to modify the word adapter to hold our color
وللقيام بذلك يجب أن أقوم بتعديل موائم النص ليحمل قيمة
resource value.
مورد اللون الخاص بنا.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
And now I'll need a modifier existing constructor to accept this new
والآن احتاج لمعدّل لقبول معرف
color resource ID as an input, and now I need to set the value of m color
مورد اللون الجديد كمدخل واحتاج الآن لوضع قيمة معرف
resource ID to be whatever input was passed in as the color resource ID.
مورد اللون لتكوين المدخل الذي تم تمريره كمعرف مورد اللون.
And then at the bottom of the give you method I need to set the color.
والآن في أسفل الوظيفة ستحتاج إلى ضبط اللون.
So that's done with this block of code here.
ويتم ذلك عبر مجموعة الكود هنا.
So first I'm setting the theme of the color for
سأقوم في البداية بضبط وضع اللون
the lists item and then I'm finding he color that the resource ID maps to and
لعناصر القوائم ثم العثور على اللون الذي يناسب معرف المورد
then finally set in the background color of the text container view.
وضبط لون الخلفية في النهاية لواجهة محتوى النص.
I know colors can be a bit tricky and
أعلم أن الألوان خادعة إلى حد ما
it did take me a couple tries to get this right.
وستسغرق منك محاولتين للقيام بذلك بشكل صحيح.
But follow along and you'll be able to do something similar in your own app.
لكن عليك المتابعة وستكون قادرًا على القيام بأمر مماثل في تطبيقك الخاص.
So now, we need a convert the color resource ID into a color value.
والآن نحتاج إلى تحويل معرف مورد اللون إلى قيمة لون.
To do this, let's head on over to the list item way out.
وللقيام بذلك لنبدأ بعناصر القائمة.
In here we need to make sure that the linear layout in the list item layout
نحتاج للتأكد من أن المخطط الخطي في مخطط صنف القائمة له
has an ID on the container.
معرف على المحتوى.
So back to the word adapter.
لنعود إلى موائم النص.
So now that we have the word adapter constructor set up to take in the color
لنقوم الآن بضبط موائم النص لوضع معرف
resource ID, we need to modify the other activities so
مورد اللون، نحتاج إلى تعديل الأنشطة الأخرى
that when we call the word adopt a constructor.
حتى يمكننا عمل مكيف النص كملائم.
We're passing the right inputs.
إننا نقوم بإدخال المدخلات الصحيحة.
So we that here in the numbers activity.
والآن نقوم بنشاط الأرقام.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
I want to add that here in the colors activity, and similarly for
أرغب في إضافة ذلك هنا في نشاط الألوان، والذي يشبه
the phrases activity and lastly for the family activity.
نشاط العبارات ونشاط العائلة في النهاية.
And one more thing before I forget.
هناك أمر آخر قبل أن أنساه.
So back on the list item layout, remember to remove the background color
لذا عد إلى مخطط عنصر القائمة وتذكر إزالة لون الخلفية
that we hard coded into list item layout.
الذي قمنا بتكويده في مخطط عنصر القائمة.
So we had set it to always appear as an orange background color behind the text,
لذا قمنا بضبطه ليظهر دائمًا باللون البرتقالي للخلفية خلف النص،
but now that we can set the color dynamically when the list items created
ويمكننا الآن ضبط اللون بشكل ديناميكي عند إنشاء عناصر القائمة
we don't need it any more.
التي لا نحتاجها بعد ذلك.
So let's test out the app now.
ولنختبر التطبيق الآن.
So let's start with numbers.
لنبدأ بالأرقام.
All right orange is expected and then family members, whoa.
البرتقالي هو اللون المتوقع ثم أفراد العائلة.
That looks really good.
يبدو ذلك رائعًا حقًا.
So going back to the colors nice and
ثم الرجوع إلى الألوان الرائعة
then lastly phrases while liking that blue.
والعبارات في النهاية أثناء القيام بذلك.
So each category shows a different color as expected and it's all coming together
توضح كل فئة لون مختلف كما هو متوقع وسيظهر ذلك.
and looking really polished now, so high five on that great job.
أنه يبدو مصقولاً الآن، تهانينا على هذا العمل الرائع.